TOMISLAV SOKAC

APP 1 Block 3D Belgrade Square West, Tallaght, Dublin 24, Ireland tsokac2@gmail.com • 085 819 68 18

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tomislav-sokac2

GitHub: https://github.com/tsokac2

SUMMARY

Meticulous Junior Front End Developer having 3 years' experience in developing personal user Interface applications and professional web applications using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript (Es5 and ES6), jQuery, and Bootstrap.

Recent Code Institute diploma in software development recipient including Microsoft Azure AZ-900 certification and progressing towards Azure DevOps solutions expert.

Strong knowledge of Python and Django framework, highly experienced in code debugging through research, testing, discovery Reddit, Stack Overflow, MDN Web Docs.

A strong communicator, organized, can read between the lines to understand business needs and prioritize work accordingly in high-pressure environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SUPPORT

Applications Active Directory, Lansweeper, Veeam B&R, SAP, CMD, RDP, Server Manager, SCCM, PowerShell

Network Freshservice Helpdesk, Teams, TeamViewer, Slack, Zoom, Cisco AnyConnect, Webex

Cloud OKTA, O365 Admin Console, VMware, Azure, Sophos, Symantec Cyber Security, MobileIron Go, Adobe Admin

OS Windows 11, Windows 10, iOS, Android, Windows Server 2012, Windows Server 2019

DEVELOPMENT

Applications Balsamiq, Photoshop, Illustrator, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Atom

Network GitHub/Git, WinSCP, FileZilla, JIRA

Languages HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Python, SQL

Frameworks Django, Flask, Bootstrap, Jasmine, Angular JS, React

Cloud AWS S3, Azure Web Services, Az AD, MongoDB, Stripe, Heroku

Methods Object-Oriented Programming, Performance Testing, Load Testing & Debugging, Responsive Design & Mobile-

First Websites, API Implementation, Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Operation Support Specialist

Exertis Global Operations, Ireland <u>exertisglobaloperations.com</u> Jan 2020 - Present

RESPONSIBILITIES

REPORTING - Control incremental, weekly, and monthly backups with Veeam Backup & Replication software.

- Monitoring health, applications, connectivity, and security for users IT assets via Lansweeper application.

- Update and maintain detailed external and internal IT documentation.

SECURITY - Symantec Endpoint enrolment with redistributable installation package for Windows and Mac devices.

- Sophos enrolment with redistributable installation package for Windows devices.

- Importing and creating default or custom security policies.

USER SUPPORT - Assist with new hire onboarding and training curriculum.

Walk users through problem-solving processes.Respond to queries via email, MS Teams, or Freshservice ticketing system.

- Supervise users for MFA configurations with personal or company mobile devices via OKTA Verify app.

SaaS - O365 Admin licensing control, SharePoint orchestration, Teams channels collections management.

- Generate DL lists, shared emails delegations, groups, user mailboxes with the Exchange admin center.

- MobileIron Android and iOS mobile device security container configuration and control.

- vSphere - VM's control and monitoring - Disaster recovery testing.

PROJECTS - Troubleshoot IT scripts, systems, or automation.

- SAP transports requests deployments with the JIRA tracking process.

- Supervising weekly e-commerce store deployments for testing, staging, and production cycles.

Desktop Support Engineer

BNP Paribas, Ireland bnpparibas.ie/en/ Apr 2019 – Jan 2020

RESPONSIBILITIES

REPORTING - Stand-up session review and planning for Windows 10 migration project target 600+ users.

- Daily migration targets according to available resources including HVD and HP G5 EliteBook.

- Monitoring Windows 10 pre-build Imaging process and reporting accordingly.

- Remote collaboration with central IT operation office regarding new system updates.

USER SUPPORT - Operational efficiencies by streamlining and automating routine work tasks in conjunction with ServiceNow.

Application updates, licenses, and subscription configurations for Adobe Creative Cloud.
Remote support via Goverlan Reach Console after successful Windows 10 migration.

SaaS - SCCM packages installation against SDG user-profile including SAP, Adobe Creative Cloud.

- O365 implementation of advanced Excel macros configuration via CMD interface.

PROJECTS - New workstations build scope control and MAC address implementation and configuration.

- Supervising and managing user HVD profiles migration from Windows 7 to Windows 10.

- Application migration respectfully from Windows 7 to Windows 10.

- Configuring Bloomberg workstation according to company standards and regulatory compliance.

Merchandising Assistant

LEMAP Ltd – Innovators in Fashion diesel.ie/ Nov 2016 – Apr 2019

Team Lead - Department of Activities

Udemy Certificate

Melia Hotels International melia.com Jun 2010 – Oct 2016

WEB PROJECTS

	STUDY	New Irish Life	Django, JS SASS, AWS S3, Stripe, Google API	newirishlife.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
		NewIrishLife-3-0	Python, JS, SASS, Google API, Email JS, MongoDB	new-irish-life-3-0.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
		NewIrishLife-2-0	jQuery, JS, SASS, Google API, Email JS	tsokac2.github.io/newlrishLife.2.0/	GitRepo
		Nexter	SASS, jQuery, CSS Grid, Flexbox	res-nexter.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
		Natours	SASS, jQuery, CSS	res-natours.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
		"Georgia"	SASS, jQuery, CSS	res-georgia.herokuapp.com/	GitRepo
Ρ	PUBLIC	New Ireland Life	JavaScript, CSS	newirelandlife.com	GitRepo
		Resume	Angular JS, SASS	tomislavsokac.com	GitRepo
		Showreel TsR	JavaScript, CSS	tomislavsokac.com/showreel.html	GitRepo

EDUCATION

FINISHED	Microsoft Certification	H939-1488	AZ-900 Azure fundamentals	Aug 2021
	Code Institute	<u>SB2008FS</u>	Diploma in Software Development	Aug 2021
	Udemy Certificate	UC-0R8PP9DZ	Advance CSS - CSS Grid - Flexbox	Oct 2019
	Udemy Certificate	UC-GD4CICQ8	SASS (CSS Pre-processor)	May 2019
	Udemy Certificate	UC-75UYCA3	Full Stack Developer	May 2019
	Udemy Certificate	UC-G19YIU5A	Photoshop – Web Design	Mar 2019
	University of Zagreb, Croatia		Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (B.C.S.)	Dec 2009
PREPARATION Microsoft Certification			AZ-204 Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure	Aug 2021
	Udemy Certificate		React & Django Full Stack	Aug 2021
PLANED Microsoft Certification		AZ-400 Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions	Oct 2021	

React - The Complete Guide

Oct 2021